UNITE Editor Photographs 6000/043 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE Editor Photographs
1977-1991
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE)
6000/043 P
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Photographs.
7669186
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 01, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 17, 2016
Biographical / Historical
UNITE, the Union of Needle Trades, Industrial, and Textile Employees was formed in 1995 after a merger between the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) and the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU).
In 2004 they announced they would merge with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) which created UNITE HERE.
Jay Mazur served as president of UNITE from its beginning until his retirement in 2001. Bruce Raynor was elected president at that time and served until the HERE merger.
Scope and Contents
This collection has over three hundred photographs and almost one hundred slides, showing members taking part in conventions and strikes.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6000 AV: UNITE Audio-Visual Collection 6000 G: UNITE Posters 6000 MB: UNITE Memorabilia 6000 P: UNITE Photographs 6000 PUBS: UNITE Publications
Hospitality industry--Employees--Labor unions; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union --Photographs; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees --Photographs; UNITE HERE (Organization) --Photographs
7669186
- AFL-CIO Convention 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  3 photographs
- AFL-CIO Convention 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  11 photographs
- AFL-CIO Convention 1991 - Detroit (Box 1, Folder 3)
  7 photographs
- Alaska (Box 1, Folder 4)
  1 photograph
- Black History Month (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Board Meetings (Box 1, Folder 6)
  19 photographs
- Canadian Labour Congress - CLC - Photos (Box 1, Folder 7)
  5 photographs
- Canadian Labour Congress (Box 1, Folder 8)
  6 photographs
- Cover photos (Box 1, Folder 9)
  8 photographs; 1 slide
- Food and Beverage Trades (Box 1, Folder 10)
  10 photographs
- IUF/NARO (Box 1, Folder 11)
  4 photographs
- JAL/NIKKO (Box 1, Folder 12)
  41 photographs
- Labor Leaders (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Marriott Hotels (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Mexican Delegation (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Miami and $5 million payback (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Miami Strike (Box 1, Folder 17)
  21 photographs
- NAACP Show - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  11 photographs; 22 slides
- New Leadership (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Niagara Casino (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 21)
  23 photographs
- Union Industries Show (Box 2, Folder 1)
  29 photographs; 54 slides -- collection re-organized -- was formerly box 1, ff 22
- Union "YES" Campaign (Box 2, Folder 2)
  9 photographs -- collection re-organized -- was formerly box 1, ff 23
- USSR (Box 2, Folder 3)
  3 photographs -- collection re-organized -- was formerly box 1, ff 24
- Williamsburg Organizing (Box 2, Folder 4)
  12 photographs -- collection re-organized -- was formerly box 1, ff 25
- Women 1975 (International Women's Year) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  33 photographs -- collection re-organized -- was formerly box 1, ff 26
- Local 35 Strike (Box 2, Folder 6)
  20 slides; 29 photographs -- collection re-organized -- was formerly box 1, ff 27
- Advertisement photographs (Box 2, Folder 7)
  4 photographs -- collection re-organized -- was formerly box 1, ff 28